Baptiste Pesquet

Software engineer | Teacher | Trainer in computer science and artificial intelligence Bordeaux, FR

Opposquet bpesquet bpesquet

I teach computer science and artificial intelligence to students and professionals since 2006. Before that, I graduated as a software engineer and worked for several years in the industry. I try my best to combine a high level of technical expertise with the pedagogical qualities needed to deliver an efficient and enjoyable learning experience.

SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE (3)

Full-time professor and trainer at ENSC - Bordeaux INP

Sep 2016 - Current

Teaching, course design and management, educational support, project monitoring, exam management, continuous training.

- Co-creator and head of the artificial intelligence specialization track since 2019.
- Responsible for the second year of study and several CS and Al courses.

Full-time professor and trainer at BTS IG/SIO, Chalon-sur-Saône, Laval, Lyon Teaching, educational support, exam management, peer training.

Sep 2006 - Aug 2016

- Education Nationale teaching examinations: passed the CAPET in 2005 and Agrégation in 2008 (ranked first).
- Member of the jury for the CAPET national teaching examination from 2016 to 2019.

Software Engineer at Artal, Toulouse

Sep 1999 - Aug 2006

Developer, tech and project lead for companies such as Airbus, Astrium and Alcatel.

EDUCATION (2)

Computer Science Engineering School at ENSIIE, Evry

1996 - 1999

Graduate engineering school ("Grande Ecole"). Majors in object-oriented programming and artificial intelligence. Competed in RoboCup'99 during final internship.

Classes Préparatoires aux Grandes Ecoles, option M at Lycée Pierre Corneille, Rouen